Downloaded from
YTS.BZ
Official YIFY movies site:
It's the police.
Simon Blackwell from Cheshire.
Can we come in? We need to speak to you.
- Yeah, come in.
- Thanks. Sorry about coming in…
- Lucy?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna come in, okay?
Please can I see my cat?
You know I didn't do it.
- I know you didn't!
- I know!
We know that!
We have gone through
the evidence case by case
and given you the opportunity
to provide explanations throughout.
You wrote a note
saying, "I am evil. I did this."
If you haven't been involved
in the collapses and deaths
of these babies,
why did you write a note
which clearly states you were responsible,
that you killed them on purpose?
No comment.
This interview is being recorded.
It's now recording every word
that is said in this interview.
Introduce yourself, please.
- Date of birth?
- Fourth of the first, 1990.
This interview is your opportunity
to put forward your response
to the reasons why you've been arrested.
If you are innocent
and have any reasonable explanation,
defense, or alibi,
we will search for evidence
that will support you.
We're not here to judge you.
Do you understand that, Lucy?
Yes.
So tell me about what happens
with a baby's first feed.
So the doctors will tell you
when they're happy
for a baby to commence feeds.
And they would be fed
via the nasogastric tube.
And we… Usually, for a premature baby,
we would prefer to give either breast milk
or donor breast milk.
We wouldn't usually give formula
to a baby of that size.
We're gonna talk about ***.
At 16:01 hours on 20th June 2015,
she was born by cesarean section
and transferred to the neonatal ward.
At 04:25 hours on 22nd June 2015,
♪ was pronounced deceased.
Is there anything you can tell us
about what happened to her?
I don't really remember ***.
You can't remember any collapse
or any involvement in the care
at that time?
No.
Are you gonna search the house?
Okay, just put your arms out for me.
What's your current occupation?
Children's nurse.
Okay, this interview is being recorded.
I am Detective Constable Lee.
- The other officer present is…
- 3201 Vikki Holt.
Please introduce yourself again
for me, Lucy.
Lucy Letby.
So, in general terms,
during the resuscitation,
what are the roles--
Usually, the medical staff
have the airway.
They would be delivering
the resuscitation drugs.
- So two people would be doing the drugs.
- Okay.
And then ideally have somebody
supporting the parents.
So who takes the notes
during the resus attempts?
Ideally, you would have a scribe there.
So, usually,
one of the junior doctors would take on,
or one of the nurses would take on
the scribing role.
Just prior to the collapse, Lucy,
had you had any cause
to go into Nursery One at all?
I don't remember.
Right. Were you working in Nursery One?
I don't think I was, but I don't recall
which baby I was looking after.
And you… you don't remember
the process of how you ended up
in Nursery One, with the resus?
No.
Are you aware
of why he required resuscitation?
No, I don't recall
the events leading up to that.
I just know that he had resuscitation.
It's the police.
Simon Blackwell from Cheshire.
Can we come in? We need to speak to you.
Lucy?
I'm gonna come in, okay?
This is a continuation
of a series of interviews, Lucy.
As you can see, the red light has come on.
This interview is
also being visually recorded
and monitored upstairs.
Your home address was searched,
and a large quantity
of these handover sheets
were found at your home address.
Can you explain that?
They're just sheets that have
inadvertently come home in my pocket.
I've not emptied my pockets
before coming home.
Explain to me why you put them
all together in a folder.
I didn't know
how to dispose of them myself,
so I didn't dispose of them.
You didn't know how to dispose of them?
No.
Have you previously taken
any of these handover sheets home
and disposed of them?
No, I don't think so.
'Cause I haven't got a shredder,
and that's how I would…
that's how I'd have to get rid of them.
Do those sheets that are in your folder
that you kept at your home address, Lucy,
relate to babies
which you were designated nurse for?
Yes.
My colleague asked you
about the collapses of the babies,
and you said that you recorded those.
- Why?
- I think I've made reference.
I don't know
in what way I've recorded them.
Right.
I think there were some days
in my diary that I've…
I've asterisked or marked days that were…
that we had a baby
that was particularly unwell.
And what was the purpose of that?
Don't know. Just for my own…
Your own what?
I don't know.
My own reflection, I suppose.
Why would you want to reflect
on those, Lucy?
I don't talk to anybody about it.
I just internalize things
and do it in my own time.
I'm gonna read you
an extract from it, and it says,
"Murderer. Murder."
"No one will ever know
what happened and why."
Explain these comments to me, Lucy.
No comment.
Tell me about the comment "murderer."
Are you suggesting there
that you are a murderer?
No comment.
Tell me about,
"No one will ever know
what happened and why."
- No comment.
- What does that mean, Lucy?
No comment.
Lucy, since you left the unit,
887 babies of 32 weeks' gestation
or greater
were born
at the Countess of Chester Hospital
and admitted to the NNU.
None of these babies since you left died
or deteriorated unexpectedly.
Have you got any comment
you wish to make about this?
No comment.
With all the evidence
we have available at this time,
it clearly shows
that you were the only person present
for all of the 25 collapses
and the deaths of the 17 babies
and would suggest you are responsible.
No one else, Lucy. Only you.
Lucy, f there is an explanation
for why you are responsible,
now is your final opportunity
to explain why this is to us.
No comment.
Okay.
Okay, the time by my watch is 16:10 hours,
and this interview is now concluded.
Is she upstairs?
We're gonna talk about ***.
There's six pages there
of her medical charts
that you've got your name next to.
Is it fair to say
you were involved somewhat with her care?
Yes.
Tell us about what happened to ***.
I don't really remember ***.
Do you recall getting involved
with the resuscitation at all?
Not that I remember.
Dr. Evans said her collapse is consistent
with the effect of an air embolus
caused by an injection of air
into her circulation
when the designated nurse
was not in the room,
but you were.
Right.
Have you got any explanation
to that, Lucy?
No.
From the evidence provided, Lucy,
it shows that you were present
when *** collapsed.
Do you agree with that?
You were working in Nursery One
when a nurse was in there.
She had gone out for a reason.
If that's what she says.
I don't recall specifically where I was.
Is there a reason why you remembered
the administering of the medication
and not the collapses, Lucy?
No, I've only remembered the medication
from looking through the notes
and seeing
that I obviously did sign for medications.
Is it because you remember
the administration of the medication?
Because that's when you took
the opportunity to attack…
No.
…and administer air?
- No.
- No?
No.
On 25th June,
you did a Facebook search for ***.
And on 25th June again,
you then searched for *****.
Do you agree you made those searches
on Facebook, Lucy?
I don't think I recall doing it,
but, yes, I must have if it's there, yeah.
Were you looking for photographs
of the babies, Lucy?
No.
- You don't know what you were looking for?
- No.
Whoever gave him his insulin
would have done so
knowing it would've placed him
in harm's way
and could have caused his death
or led to him having
irreversible life-changing injuries.
Do you agree with that statement, Lucy?
Yes.
You've confirmed your signature
on the TPN prescription.
- Did you administer…
- No.
- …insulin into the bags of TPN, Lucy?
The question to you is,
did you administer insulin?
No.
Because the experts think someone has.
You were caring for him.
I didn't.
- Do you know who did?
- No.
You wrote a note saying,
"I am evil. I did this."
"I don't deserve to live."
"I killed them on purpose."
"I am a horrible, evil person."
Explain why this is to us.
No comment.
The jury in the trial
of the nurse Lucy Letby
has retired to consider its verdict.
Okay, Lucy, I am really concerned
about what you've written down
and what you've implied you might've done.
Anything you want to tell us?
I just wrote it
'cause everything had got on top of me.
It was when I had not long found out
I'd been removed from the unit.
I felt like they were…
blaming my practice,
that I might have hurt them
without knowing, through my practice,
and that made me feel guilty.
Do you want to elaborate on
some of the things you put down on there?
I was blaming myself.
But not because I'd done something.
Because of the way
people were making me feel.
I felt like I'd only ever done my best
for those babies,
and then people were trying to say
that my practice wasn't good
or that I'd done something,
and I just… I couldn't cope with it.
And I did just not wanna be here anymore.
You say, "There are no words.
"I can't breathe. I can't focus."
I just felt like it was all just
spiraling out of control.
I just didn't know how to feel about it
or what was gonna happen or what to do.
Just felt that the trust and the team
were trying to imply
that it was something that I'd done.
Was there any individuals
that… implied that?
Yeah, some of the consultants.
Can you give a reason why
they might wanna victimize you or…
point the finger towards you?
It crossed my mind at times whether
they were trying to put the blame on me
for something that somebody else had done.
In terms of overwhelming fear and panic,
what were you afraid of?
That they were going to think
I had done something wrong.
Okay, and what would happen
if they thought that?
That this would happen.
- Right.
- That the police would get involved.
- And is that what happened--
- And I'd lose my job.
And was it a job that you enjoyed?
Yeah.
Yeah, I loved my job.
Okay.
We've spent several days
questioning and discussing with you
in depth
your involvement in the murders
and attempted murders of 17 babies,
which you have constantly denied, Lucy.
Have you got any comment you wish to make?
No comment.